Guide to the Jacqueline End Papers, 1965-2012 and undated RL.00363
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jacqueline End papers
1965-2012 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
End, Jacqueline
RL.00363
3 Linear Feet
Advertising copy writer and creative executive for a number of agencies, including: Doyle Dane Bernbach; Wells Rich Greene; Foote, Cone & Belding; TBWA/Chiat/Day. Primarily examples of creative work, including print advertisements and proofs, design layouts and sketches, photographs, correspondence and printed materials. Non-paper formats include audiotape, videocassettes, audio cassettes, DAT, CD-R and DVD-R. Clients represented include Absolut, Ascencia (Bayer), Bali and Wonderbra (now part of Hanes family of brands), K-Mart, L'Oreal, Nivea, Ralston Purina, Ricoh, Sara Lee, Sega, Trojan (Church & Dwight) and Volkswagen. Agencies represented include Doyle Dane Bernbach, Foote Cone & Belding, Forman End Dolleck, Kaplan Thaler, TBWA/Chiat/Day and Wells Rich Greene. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
900 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jacqueline End Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012.
Collection Overview
The Jacqueline End Papers span the years 1965-2012 and consist primarily of examples of End's creative work, including print advertisements and proofs, design layouts and sketches, photographs, correspondence and printed materials that document her advertising career with a number of agencies, including Doyle Dane Bernbach, Foote Cone & Belding, Forman End Dolleck, Kaplan Thaler, TBWA/Chiat/Day and Wells Rich Greene. Non-paper formats include audiotape, videocassettes, audio cassettes, DAT, CD-R and DVD-R. Clients represented include Absolut, Ascencia (Bayer), Bali and Wonderbra (now part of Hanes family of brands), K-Mart, L'Oreal, Nivea, Ralston Purina, Ricoh, Sara Lee, Sega, Trojan (Church & Dwight) and Volkswagen.
Collection Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Accounts and General Files, Photographs, Printed Materials, Large-Format Materials, and Audiovisual Materials.
Related Material
Foote, Cone & Belding Communications Inc. Records
J. Walter Thompson Company Rena Bartos Papers
Lore Parker Papers
Margaret Fishback Papers
Wells Rich Greene Records
Advertising; Photographs; Videocassettes; CD-Rs; DVDs; Advertising executives; Audiocassettes; Advertising -- History; Advertising -- United States -- History; Sega Enterprises; Sara Lee Corporation; Ricoh Company; Doyle Dane Bernbach Inc.; End, Jacqueline, d. 2012; Bic Pen Corp; Church & Dwight; Absolut Vodka Company; Bayer AG; Nivea; Ralston Purina Company; K-Mart Corporation; L'Oréal (Firm); Hanes Menswear, Inc.; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; End, Jacqueline; Foote, Cone & Belding
- Accounts and General Files, 1965-2012 and undated
  - ABC Carpet, radio script, undated (Box 1)
  - Absolut, 1999-2002 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Arm & Hammer, undated (Box 1)
  - Ascencia (Bayer), 2005 (Box 1)
  - Bayamo restaurant, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Children, undated (Box 1)
  - Creative miscellaneous, 1972-1984 (Box 1)
  - Creative portfolio, 2004and undated (Box 1)
  - DDB 60s reunion, 2011 (Box 1)
  - eBeanstalk.com (Child Development Corp.), releases, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Fast Company, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Financial services, undated (Box 1)
  - Kid ideas, 1975-1989 and undated (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1965-1998 (Box 1)
  - Memorial notice, 2011 (Box 1)
  - Miami Ad School, 1996-2001 (Box 1)
  - Monet jewelry, undated (Box 1)
  - Nintendo Game Boy, undated (Box 1)
  - Pringles, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Resume, undated (Box 1)
  - Schmuzzdorf, 1981and undated (Box 1)
  - Science Park (New Haven), undated (Box 1)
  - Speech--New Haven Ad Club, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Storyboards and print layouts (Peace Corps, Plus toothpaste, Sanka, Sealy-Posturpedic, Tang), undated (Box 1)
  - U.S. News and World Report, undated (Box 1)
  - Voices (radio auditions), 2006 (Box 1)
- Photographs, 1993 and undated
  - Absolut outdoor, undated (Box 2)
  - Bic Banana shoot and others, undated (Box 2)
  - Haagen Dazs win party, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Miami Ad School shoot and Carlos family, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
- Printed Material, 1968-2005 and undated
  - 50 Best Creatives, 1972 (Box 3)
  - AAF Addy Awards, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Andy Awards, 1987-2002 (Box 3)
  - Communication Arts Exhibition, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Flush, 2002 Summer (Box 3)
  - Honor through Bleach: The Obsessive Compulsive's Guide to Cleaning Like an Italian Housewife, by Jackie (Arlotta) End, 2012 (Box 3)
  - I Am Martell, undated (Box 3)
  - London International Advertising Awards, 2001 (Box 3)
  - OAAA Obie Awards, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - One Show Festival, 2001, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Shots, 2001 Jan. (Box 3)
  - The Freakie Magnet (Cocoa Freakies cereal), 1994 (Box 3)
  - Why Do You Always Have To Say Please (Wendy Rosea and Jackie End), 2005 (Box 3)
- Large-Format Materials
  - Absolut newsprint advertising, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Absolut outdoor, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
  - Awards
    - Art Directors Club, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Clio, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
    - London International Advertising Awards, 1987 (Box 4)
    - One Club, 2001 (Box 4)
    - One Show, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Creative portfolio
    - Absolut, undated (Box 4)
    - Nivea, Wonderbra, undated (Box 4)
  - Miami Ad School, 1996-2000 (Box 4)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 4)
  - Print layouts, Eve shaving crème, undated (Box 4)
  - Royal Caribbean Cruise Line, undated (Box 4)
  - Sketches, 1968 and undated (Box 4)
  - Storyboards and print layouts (Hazel Bishop lipstick, Sanka), undated (Box 4)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1970-2011 and undated
  - 3-Fingered Louie: Opti-Free agency mix. 2003. DAT. (Box 5)
  - ABC Carpet: Female. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Absolut
    - Collects, woodstock, Furst, Squeeze, Expansion, Truth print art. 2002. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Good Morning America feature. 2001. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Quark files. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Truth and other print files. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Truth. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Alcon
    - Faces agency version. 2004. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Opti-Free art. 2004. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Opti-Free print advertisements. 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Television spots. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Aricept
    - Aricept and Alcon print and television. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Work files. 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Art & Copy. 2006. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Ascencia/Contour. 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Backups #2. [List with disc.] 2006. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Backups. [List with disc.] 2003-2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Bali
    - Let Bali Embrace You. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - The First Underwear; Tree of Style; Let Bali Embrace You (2 tapes). 1998. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Barnes & Noble
    - Script reads. 1999. DAT. (Box 5)
    - Voiceover edits. 1999. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Bic
    - Banana data dvd. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Banana nine spots. 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Banana with Mel Brooks. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Brain (Bill Montgomery). Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Softtwin, logos, pendant. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Sure Start Lighter: Loaner. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Boscovs: Meet the Family; Bride; TV; Fashion Customer. Undated. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Brazil
    - #1 compilation. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - #2 compilation. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Compilations
    - Alcon; Absolut; agency business; other. 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Alcon; Nivea. 2004. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Bali; Wonderbra; Nivea. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Beauty, fashion, OTC/OFX print. 2002. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Before and After [List with disc.] 1996-1998CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Chuck Furgies; Honor; Flowers for email; Freakies packaging. 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Copy and art scans [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Copy files [List with disc.] 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Copy scans unfinished [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - G4 files [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Historical and recent Quicktime files [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Jackie End 1 of 3 [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Jackie End 2 of 3 [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Jackie End 3 of 3: Web and radio [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Kmart; Freakies. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - L'Oreal; Boscovs. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - L'Oreal; Jackie vignette; Freakies. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - MPGs. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - My Office Files [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Nivea Soft: Summer Rain, Inspired, Juggling; Bayer Contour: Dots; Bayer Breeze: Flower. Undated. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - NWMB; Nivea; Bic. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - OFX: Faces; Nivea: Gisele, Night Routine; Bic Softwin: Soccer, Subway; Barely There: Sensual Revolution. Undated. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Olay; Miss Clairol; Klorane; Chiat RCCL montage. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Print scans [List with disc.] 2002. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Print/TV CD#1 [List with disc.] 2006. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Print/TV CD#2 [List with disc.] 2006. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Print/TV CD#5 [List with disc.] 2006. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Scans: Bic; Godiva. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Sharpei, Gisele, original and print [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Special Dinners; Bic. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Spots for Web and DVD [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Spots for Web and DVD--18 spots [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Spots for Web and DVD--44 spots [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Spots for Web and DVD--A dupe 43 spots [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Tender Vittles; Safeguard; Lovestick; Kmart; Karmann Ghia; Eau de Love. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - U.S. News; Olay; Natori; Dutch Boy; Gaines Burgers. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Visine; Tender Vittles; Optifree; NWMB; MLB; Food Emporium. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Wells Rich Greene commercials 1966-1998 [List with tape] 1998. VHS. (Box 5)
    - Work 2 [List with disc.] 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Work 3 [List with disc.] 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Work 5 [List with disc.] 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Work 6 [List with disc.] 2005. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Work art. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Work: Accounts ACI- [List with disc.] 2005. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Dole: Cereal/Nabisco. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Doyle Dane Bernbach (DDB)
    - 1960s Creative Reunion photos. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - 1960s Creative Reunion. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - 1960s Creative Reunion--Historical Creative. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - 1960s Creative Reunion--Welcome Home video. 2011. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Dunkin' Donuts: The Coffee Scene. 1995. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - eBeanstalk
    - Ads [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Big Top; Hippo; Mind Shapes; Mobile; Spiral; Wagon. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - MPGs [List with disc.] 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - QT files (2 discs) 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - SD master [List with tape] 2007. Digibeta. (Box 5)
    - Small files for YouTube. 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Spots for DVD players. 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Voiceovers (2 discs). Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Zolo Accent. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - FCB Ken Sugarman: Strategy speech. 1984. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Forman End Dolleck: Presentation reel. Undated. VHS. (Box 5)
  - Freakies
    - Backup. 1995. DAT. (Box 5)
    - Commercials 23 minutes. 1995. VHS. (Box 5)
    - Website music. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Frito Lay: Rumbles. 1986. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Gatorade: Bumblebee; Dancehall. 1970. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Grandma's: Jackie's voice. 1985. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Gulf Lite Briquets: Bad BBQ'er with Portuguese ending. 1996. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Haagen Dazs: Reserved for Haagen Dazs.2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Heaven story--J. Arlotta. Undated. 1/4 audiotape. (Box 5)
  - JBT. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - K-Mart
    - Friends; New Mother; Everyday Low Prices. 1991. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - The Urge; Man's Work Is Never Done. 1991. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Various [List with disc.] 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Lenscrafters pitch. 2005. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Long term #1 [List with disc.] Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - L'Oreal
    - Biwi. 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Superior Preference (5 discs) 2008. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Mel Brooks: From CD (2 tapes). 2000. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Miami Ad School: Rough Cuts. Undated. VHS. (Box 5)
  - NatWest: Demo revised. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Nivea
    - AAP MR jobs. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Blueprint; Bad Things; Wrinkled Paper. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Expressionless (2 tapes). 1999. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Girlfriends; Time. 1998. DAT. (Box 5)
    - Gisele (2 discs). Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Inspired TV. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Print/TV CD3 [List with disc.] 2006. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Reshaping. Undated. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Still Here; Reshaping. Undated. DVD-R. (Box 5)
    - Various print/radio/television--4 discs [Lists with discs.] 2005-2006 and undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Visage print. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Visage Q10 Wrinkle Control; Movie; Expressionless. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - OFX
    - Brunette photo only. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Redhead art only. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Olay: Water glams. Undated. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Partners & Shevack: New Business, Talking to Women. 1994. VHS. (Box 5)
  - Refreshing Things; Cleaner Clean radio. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - RevlonPDFs and Quark files. 2007. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Ricoh
    - Ricoh Around; Rocco & Ricoh; Birthday Ricoh. 1986. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Thinks; Gift. 1986. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Thinks; Little Things; Seal; Golf. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Royal Caribbean Cruise Lines
    - Little Things. 1987. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Mexico Sale. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Ruben. 2000. DAT. (Box 5)
  - Sara Lee
    - Barbecue; Canadian Bacon; Pizza. 1988. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Lighter Side; Are You Ready for Sara Lee? 1990. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Scans S-Z copy. 2007. DVD-R. (Box 5)
  - Sega Channel
    - A Modest Proposal. 1995. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Earthworm Jim 2. 1996. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Shane v. Carlton; Indoor Olympiad. 1996. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Winter Tune-In. 1995. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
  - Sharpei. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - TBWA/Chiat/Day
    - Chiat Back in Town (2 tapes). Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - Your Year 2000 at TBWA/Chiat/Day New York. 2000. VHS. (Box 5)
  - Trojan/Elexa
    - [no title] 2007. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - 24 [List with disc.] 2007. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - 4 spots. 2006. CD-R. (Box 5)
    - Macho; Glow; 50%; Condom Queen; also U.S. Bank, Gift Giver radio (3 discs). Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - TV Land: Presents the Greatest Commercials of All Time. Undated. VHS. (Box 5)
  - U.S. Bank. 2006. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Underwater Schaty Hi Res. Undated. CD-R. (Box 5)
  - Unidentified
    - Customer service call. Undated. Audiocassette. (Box 5)
    - We Had a Good Time; Lenny; Dirty Little Billy; They Called Him Kid; One True Love. Undated. 1/4 audiotape. (Box 5)
  - Wells Rich Greene: Agency seminar. Undated. 1/4 audiotape. (Box 5)